Welcome back. In this video, I'm going to show how to use regular expressions to
欢迎回来。在本视频中，我将演示如何使用正则表达式
specify different aspects of programming languages. Must begin with the keywords
指定编程语言的不同方面。必须以关键字开头
and this serves a relatively simple case and I'll just do it for three keywords.
这是一个相对简单的例子，我只针对三个关键字这样做。
I'll write a regular expression for if, else, or then and it would be obvious how
我将为If、Else或Then编写一个正则表达式，很明显
to do it for more. So let's write a regular expression for if and that would
为了更多的钱去做这件事。那么让我们为if编写一个正则表达式，这将
be under regular expression for i. And followed by the regular expression for f
位于i的正则表达式下，后跟f的正则表达式
and we're taking the concatenation of these two. And then we're going to union
我们把这两个连接起来。然后我们要去联合
that with the regular expression for else and what is that? Well, else consist of
用Else的正则表达式，那是什么呢？嗯，其他的包括
four individual characters so we have to write out a concatenation of those four
四个单独的字符，所以我们必须写出这四个字符的串联
characters. And, as you can see this is a little bit verbose with all of these
人物。正如您所看到的，所有这些内容都有点冗长
quotes and kind of messy to read. So in fact, there's a short hand that's normally
语录和读起来有点乱七八糟。所以事实上，通常有一只手很短
used and let me switch over to that right now. So if I want to write the regular
二手的，让我现在就切换到那个。所以如果我想写常规的
expression for a sequence of single character expressions, I could just
表达式，我可以只使用一个单字符表达式序列
[inaudible] around the outermost characters in the sequence. So for example
在序列中最外面的字符周围[听不见]。举个例子
most of the tools that let you write this, I put a quote at the beginning right IF
大多数让你写这篇文章的工具，我在开头加了一个引号，如果
and then I close quote and this means exactly The same thing as this. This is
然后我结束引用，这和这个意思完全一样。这是
the concatenation of two single character regular expression and similarly for else,
两个单字符正则表达式连接，对于ELSE类似，
And similarly for them. And if I have more keywords I'll just write them out and
对他们来说也是如此。如果我有更多的关键词，我会把它们写出来
union them altogether. Now, let's consider a slightly more complicated example. Let's
把他们完全联合起来。现在，让我们考虑一个稍微复杂一点的例子。我们走吧
think about how to specify the integers who want to be the non-empty strings of
考虑一下如何指定想要作为的非空字符串的整数
digits. So the first problem here is to write out what a digit is and that's
数字。所以这里的第一个问题是写出数字是什么，那就是
pretty straight forward. A digit is just any of the individual characters zero
非常直截了当。数字只是单个字符零中的任何一个
through nine and we already know how to write out single character regular
过了九点，我们已经知道怎么写单字规则了
expressions. And it's just a union of ten of those to specify this and it'll take me
表情。而这只是十个人的联合来具体说明这一点，这将需要我
just a moment to finish. Here we go. So that's a regular expression for the set of
稍等片刻就结束了。我们开始吧。所以这是集合的正则表达式
strings correspondin g to all the single digits. And because we want to refer to
与所有单个数字相对应的字符串。因为我们想要引用
this from time to time and also because as a very common thing to watch too, most
这是时不时的，也是因为作为一件非常平常的事情，大多数
tools have a facility for naming regular expressions. So for example I can name
工具具有命名正则表达式的功能。举个例子，我可以说出
this one to be digit so a single digital is anything that is generated or is in the
此数字为数字，因此单个数字是生成的或位于
set denoted by this regular expression. And now what we want to do is to have
由此正则表达式表示的集合。现在我们想要做的是
multiple digits. Well, we know a way to do that. We can just iterate a single digit
多位数。我们知道一个方法可以做到这一点。我们可以只迭代一个数字
as many times as we like. And so here we get all strings, all possible strings of
我们想要多少次都行。所以这里我们得到了所有字符串，所有可能的字符串
digits and this is very, very close to what we wanted except that the string that
数字，这非常非常接近我们想要的，除了字符串
we want has to be non-empty. We don't want to count the empty string as an integer.
我们想要的必须是非空的。我们不想将空字符串算作整数。
And there's an easy way to do that. We just say that the whole sequence has to
有一个简单的方法可以做到这一点。我们只是说整个序列必须
begin with a single digit and then it's followed by zero or more additional digits
以单个数字开头，然后是零个或多个附加数字
so just. Is just to reiterate that, we see there has to be at least one digit and is
所以只要。只是重申一下，我们看到必须至少有一个数字，而且是
followed by zero more additional digits. And this pattern actually for a given
后跟零个附加数字。这个模式实际上对于给定的
language is extremely common. So if I wanted to say that I have at least one a I
语言是非常普遍的。所以如果我想说我至少有一个
write that as a, a because this has zero or more a, the second part is zero more
写成a，a，因为这里有零个或更多的a，第二部分是零
a's and the first part says there has to be at least one a. And because this is so
第一部分说必须至少有一个。因为这就是
common, there's a short hand for it. I think is supported by every regular
普通的，有一种简略的说法。我想每个常客都会支持的
expression processor and that is to write a plus. An a + means is just, is just a
表达式处理器，那就是写一个加号。a+的意思是公正，就是一个
short hand for a star. And so we can actually simplify this regular expression
明星的速记。所以我们实际上可以简化这个正则表达式
a bit and write simply digit plus. Now, let's look at yet another example even
加一位，写成简单的数字加。现在，让我们再来看另一个例子
more sophisticated than the, the previous two. Let's think about how to define the
比前两个更老练。让我们考虑一下如何定义
identifiers which are strings of letters or digits that begin with a letter. And so
标识符，是以字母开头的字母或数字字符串。因此，
we already know how to do digits so let's focus on the letters for a moment. So how
我们已经知道如何做数字了，所以让我们把注意力集中在字母上。那么是怎么做到的呢？
we write out a regular expression for the letters while we're gonna name it. So
我们为字母写出一个正则表达式，然后再给它命名。所以
we'll say that the letters or actually a single letter. And now we have to write a
我们会说这些字母或者实际上是一个字母。现在我们要写一个
regula r expression for all the individual letters and that's, you know
所有单个字母的正则表达式，这就是，你知道的
straightforward but tedious. We have to say little a, lower case b, lower case c,
直截了当但冗长乏味。我们必须说小写a，小写b，小写c，
lower case d. And well, as you can see, this is gonna be rather a large regular
小写d。如你所见，这将是一个相当大的规则
expression. We're going to have 26 lower case letters and 26 upper case letters and
表达式。我们将有26个小写字母和26个大写字母，
the whole thing is going to be rather tedious as to write down so let's actually
整个事情要写下来会相当单调乏味，所以我们实际上
not do that. Instead, let me mention a shorthand, A tool support to make it
不要那样做。取而代之的是，让我提一提速记，一种制作它的工具支持
easier to write out exactly this kind of regular expression which is called the
更容易准确地写出这种正则表达式，这种正则表达式称为
character range. So inside your square brackets I can write a range of
字符范围。所以在你的方括号里我可以写一系列
characters. So how do I do that? Well, I have the starting character and an ending
人物。那我该怎么做呢？嗯，我有开头的角色和结尾
character and I separate them by a hyphen. And what this means is the union of all
字符，我用连字符将它们分开。这意味着所有人的联合
the single character, regular expressions beginning with the first character and
单个字符、从第一个字符开始的正则表达式和
ending with the second character, so everything in between. So this is exactly
以第二个字符结尾，所以中间的所有东西。所以这就是
the regular expression for all the lower case letters and then I can have another
所有小写字母的正则表达式，然后我可以有另一个
character range and so at the same square brackets for all the upper case letters.
字符范围，因此所有大写字母都在相同的方括号中。
So A through Z, Okay? And this regular expression here on the right defines
所以从A到Z，好吗？右边的这个正则表达式定义了
exactly the big union that I didn't wanna write out, okay? And that gives us a
就是我不想写出来的大工会，好吗？这给了我们一个
definition of the single letter and now we're in great shape. We are, we already
单个字母的定义，现在我们的状态很好。我们是，我们已经
have definition for a digit, we already now we have definition for letter and so
有了数字的定义，我们现在已经有了字母的定义，所以
that we can write out the rest of this definition. So we want the whole Regular
我们可以写出这个定义的睡觉。所以我们想要整个普通的
expression to always begin with a letter. Okay, so identify always begins with a
表达式始终以字母开头。好的，所以标识总是以一个
letter and after that is allowed to be a string of letters or digits, okay? So they
字母之后可以是一串字母或数字，好吗？所以他们
are suggest that there's going to be a union. So After the first letter we can
暗示将会有一个工会。所以在第一封信之后我们可以
have either a letter or a digit and then we can have an arbitrary string of those
有一个字母或一个数字，然后我们就可以有一个由它们组成的任意字符串
things. So we put a start on the whole thing and that is the definition of
一些事情。所以我们从整个事情开始，这就是
identifier. Begins with a single letter and it's followed by zero or more letters
标识符。以单个字母开头，后跟零个或多个字母
and digits. So. Because we're doing a complete lexical specification, we also
和数字。所以。因为我们正在做一个完整的词汇规范，我们还
have to deal with even the parts of the string that we're not really interested
即使是我们不太感兴趣的字符串部分也要处理
in. We have to have at least specification of them so then we can recognize and throw
在……里面。我们至少要有它们的详细说明，这样我们才能识别并抛出
them away. In particular we have to be able to recognize the white space and.
把他们带走。特别是，我们必须能够识别空格和。
We're just gonna take white space to be a non-empty sequence of blanks, new lines
我们只需要将空格作为一个非空的空格、换行符序列
and tabs even though there are other kinds of white space characters. Things like
和制表符，即使还有其他类型的空格字符。像这样的事情
maybe like rubout. Depending on your keyboard, there might be others but these
也许就像鲁比特一样。根据您的键盘，可能会有其他键盘，但这些键盘除外
three will suffice to illustrate all the important points. So, you know, blank is
三个足以说明所有重要的观点。所以，你知道，空白是
relatively easy to write down. That's just a single quote around the blank space but
相对容易写下来。这只是空白处的单引号，但是
there's a problem with new line in tab. Because a new line that carries return in
制表符中的新行有问题。因为一条新线路承载着回程
the file has special meaning typically. You know, and on the line, you end
该文件通常具有特殊的含义。你知道，在电话线上，你结束了
whatever command you're working on in this regular expression tools like SQL tools.
您在此正则表达式工具(如SQL工具)中使用的任何命令。
And, you know, tab also is not an easy thing to write down and it doesn't look
而且，你知道，标签也不是一件容易写下来的东西，而且它看起来也不是一件容易的事情
much different from a blank in a lot of cases. So, what tools do is they provide
在很多情况下与空白有很大不同。所以，工具所做的就是提供
separate name for these and it's, and typically it's done by having some kind of
它们的名字是分开的，通常情况下，它是通过某种形式的
escape character and a backslash. Is the most common one that's used and then
转义字符和反斜杠。是最常用的一种，然后
followed by a name for the character? So back slash n is typically used for new
后面跟着角色的名字？因此Back劈开n通常用于新建
line and back slash t is typically used for tab. And I just want to stress I mean
线和背劈开测试通常用于制表符。我只想强调一下，我是说
the reason for doing this example is to illustrate this that. We have to have a
做这个例子的原因是为了说明这一点。我们必须要有一个
way of naming some characters that don't really have a very nice print
给一些字体不是很漂亮的人物起名字的方法
representation. There are other characters that, that don't even have really any kind
代理。还有其他的角色，甚至没有任何类型的角色
of print representation and we still need a way to talk about them in our regular
我们仍然需要一种在我们的日常生活中谈论它们的方式
expressions because them might be embedded in a file that we have to lexically
表达式，因为它们可能嵌入到我们必须在词法上
analyze at some point. And so anyway, the way this is done is by providing a
在某一时刻进行分析。所以不管怎样，要做到这一点的方法是提供一个
separate. Naming scheme for such on principal characters and typically as the
分开。主要字符上的此类的命名方案，通常为
one that escape sequence. So, something beginning with special character like back
一个转义序列。所以，以特殊字符开头的东西，比如Back
slash followed by the name of the character. So, n for new line and this
劈开后面跟角色的名字。所以，n代表新行和这个
case nt for tab. And so to finish off our definition, this gives us. You know? One
用于标签的案例NT。为了完成我们的定义，这给了我们。你知道?一
character, white space and then we want a non empty sequence or such things so we
字符、空格，然后我们想要一个非空的序列或诸如此类的东西，所以我们
could wrap the whole union there in parenthesis and put a plus on it and that.
可以把整个工会放在括号里，然后给它加个加号。
Get us what we want. Let's pause for a moment in discussing programming languages
给我们想要的东西。让我们暂停一下讨论编程语言
and look at another example of using regular expressions from a different
中使用正则表达式的另一个示例。
domain. Here I have an e-mail address and as it turns out, e-mail addresses form a
域。这里我有一个电子邮件地址，结果是，电子邮件地址的格式是
regular language and every e-mail processing device in the world. So your
常规语言和世界上每一种电子邮件处理设备。所以你的
mailer and the mail servers that you use, all do regular expression processing to
Mailer和您使用的邮件服务器都执行正则表达式处理
understand what the e-mail address is telling them in the e-mail messages that
了解电子邮件地址在电子邮件消息中告诉他们的信息
they go by. And. And so we can think of an e-mail address is being, is consisting of
他们路过。和。所以我们可以认为电子邮件地址是由
four different strings separated by punctuation. There's a username and then
由标点符号分隔的四个不同字符串。有一个用户名，然后
three parts to the domain. Okay. Let's just assume for simplicity that the
域有三个部分。好吧。为了简单起见，我们假设
strings only consist of letters and practice they can consist of other kinds
字符串只由字母组成，练习它们可以由其他类型组成
of characters too but let's just keep things simple and we can write out the
也可以，但是让我们简单一点，我们可以写出
more complicated things using the regular expressions but the structure would be the
使用正则表达式处理更复杂的事情，但其结构将是
same as if we just consider them to be made of letters. And then these four
就好像我们认为它们是由字母组成的一样。然后这四个人
strings are separated by punctuations so there's the @ sign and to decimal points
字符串由标点符号分隔，因此有@符号和小数点
that's. Form the separators of the strings so these is a relatively straightforward
也就是说，形成字符串的分隔符，所以这是一个相对简单的
thing to write a regular expression for given what we know so far so the user name
为给定我们到目前为止所知的用户名编写正则表达式
would be the non-empty sequence of letters and then that would be followed by an @
将是非空的字母序列，然后是@
sign. And then the first part of the domain will also be on empty sequence of
签名。然后域的第一部分也将在空序列上
letters followed by a dot and then the rest is just the same. Hey, so here we're
字母后面跟着一个点，然后睡觉也是一样的。嘿，所以我们在这里
quite concisely, we had specified large family of e-mail addresses. As I said in
简而言之，我们指定了一大类电子邮件地址。正如我在
reality the e-mail addresses are slightly more complicated but they can be written
实际上，电子邮件地址稍微复杂一些，但它们可以写成
out with just a slightly more complicated regular expression. Finally for our last
只需要稍微复杂一点的正则表达式就可以了。最后是我们最后一次
example, let's look at a fragment of the lexical specification of a real
例如，让我们看一段真实的
programming language and this case that language is Pascal which is in the
编程语言，在这种情况下，该语言是Pascal，它在
[inaudible] family of languages, Pascal is an early example of a type language and
[听不见]语系，帕斯卡是一种类型语言的早期例子，
it's in the same general family as Fortran and C. And in this particular fragment of
它与Fortran和C属于同一个一般家族，并且在这个特定的片段中
pascal deals with the definition of numbers and so let's take a look here.
帕斯卡研究数字的定义，让我们看看这里。
I'll start at the bottom and look at what the overall definition of a number is. So
我将从底部开始，看看数字的整体定义是什么。所以
a number consist of three things, some digits, and I'll just read out this
一个数字由三个东西组成，一些数字，我就读出这个
abbreviation and optional fraction. And an optional exponent so we're dealing here
缩写和可选分数。和一个可选的指数，所以我们在这里处理
with floating point numbers and so a floating point number have a bunch of
浮点数，所以一个浮点数有一串
digits and then it can be followed possibly by a fraction or not and that
数字，然后它可以后跟分数，可能是小数，也可能不是
could be followed possibly by an exponent or not and. And the idea, although we
后面可能跟指数，也可能不跟指数。这个想法，虽然我们
can't see it just for this particular definition is that either of action or the
我看不到这一点，因为这个特殊的定义是动作或
exponent can be present independent of the other. So, now let's work briefly from the
指数可以独立于另一个而存在。那么，现在让我们从
bottom up, let's just check the digits on what we expect. So a single digit is in
从下往上，让我们检查一下我们期望的数字。所以输入的是一个单位数
fact the union of all the common digits just as we would hope. And then a
事实上，正如我们所希望的那样，所有公共数字的结合。然后是一个
non-empty sequence of digit is a digit plus so this is what we've already seen.
非空的数字序列是一个数字加，这就是我们已经看到的。
And now the interesting bid is to look at how the optional fraction and the optional
现在有趣的是看看可选分数和可选分数
exponent are defined and the optional fraction looks a little less scary so
指数被定义，可选分数看起来就不那么可怕了，所以
let's do that one first. So what's going on inside the fraction, well if we have a
我们先做那个吧。那么分数内部发生了什么，如果我们有一个
decimal fraction, there is gonna be a decimal point and that's gonna be followed
小数部分，会有一个小数点，然后紧随其后
by strong of digits so this is just. The fractional parts of the floating point
通过强数字，所以这是公正的。浮点的小数部分
number it's just of it comes after the decimal point. And what's this plus
数字，只是它在小数点之后。还有什么是外加的呢？
epsilon doing out here? Well remember, the plus is union and epsilon stands for the
埃普西隆在这里做什么？记住，加号是Union，epsilon代表
empty string. So what this is saying is that either the fractional portion of the
空字符串。所以这就是说，要么是小数部分
number is present or it's completely absent. So this is how you say something
数字存在或完全不存在。所以这就是你说话的方式
is optional. You write out the regular expression for the thing and then you do
是可选的。你写出这个东西的正则表达式，然后你就可以
plus epsilon at the end and that means well, either everything I said before it
加上末尾的epsilon，意思是，我之前说的每一件事
can be there or nothing is there. Okay? And the optional exponent is structured
可能在那里，或者什么都没有。好吧?并构造可选指数
similarly but somewhat more complex. So, you can see the whole exponent is optional
类似的，但稍微复杂一些。所以你可以看到整个指数是可选的
because there's some regular expression here. That's union with epsilon, And so
因为这里有一些正则表达式。这是与epsilon的结合，所以
either Something is there and this is the optional, or this exponent part or is not
要么是某个东西在那里，这是可选的，要么是这个指数部分，或者不是
present at all. And now let's look inside how the exponents define if it's there.
一点也不会出现。现在让我们来看看指数是如何定义它是否存在的。
So, an exponent always begins with e. So this is exponent, you know, standard
指数总是以e开头。所以这是指数，你知道，标准的
exponent notation and it always has a non-empty string of digits. So there's e
指数表示法，并且它始终具有非空的数字字符串。所以这里有e
followed by some digits and in between, there's an optional sign. We know the sign
后面跟着一些数字，中间有一个可选的符号。我们知道这个标志
is optional because epsilon is one of the possibilities. The whole, the whole sign
是可选的，因为epsilon是可能性之一。整个，整个标志
might be absent. And one of the possibilities for the sign, well, it could
可能会缺席。而标志的一种可能性，嗯，它可能
be negative or it could be positive. So, either there's a positive or negative sign
可以是负面的，也可以是正面的。所以，要么有积极的迹象，要么有消极的迹象
or no sign. In which case, presumably, it's interpreted to be positive. Now this
或者没有迹象。在这种情况下，想必，它被解释为积极的。现在这个
idiom where we have + epsilon indicate that something is optional is also
我们有+epsilon表示某事是可选的成语也是
extremely common and so there's another short hand that many tools provide so
非常常见，所以还有另一个捷径，很多工具都提供了这样的功能
another way of writing this, that's common is to say that. That's my fractional
写这个的另一种方式，通常是这样说的。那是我的分数
component and then it might be absent. So the question mark after a regular
组件，则该组件可能不存在。所以在一个常规事件之后的问号
expression just means exactly this construction, that we take that regular
表达式的意思就是这个结构，也就是说我们取那个正则表达式
expression and we or with epsilon. And so this one, this regular expression is a, is
表达式和我们或与ε。所以这个，这个正则表达式是一个，
a little more complicated. There's two optional components so let's just write
稍微复杂一点。有两个可选组件，所以我们只需编写
out what that would look like so we would have the exponent begins with e and then
得出它看起来是什么样子，所以我们会有指数以e开头，然后
we have a sign. Which is either + or - and that's optional so we put a question mark
我们有个信号。要么是+，要么是-这是可选的，所以我们打了一个问号
after it followed by a non-empty string or digits and then this whole thing is
在它后面跟一个非空字符串或数字，然后整个事情就是
optional. The whole exponent is optional. S o this is an alternative and more
可选。整个指数是可选的。所以这是另一种选择
compact way to write this expression. To wrap up, I, I always convinced you in this
编写此表达式的紧凑方式。总而言之，我，我一直让你相信这一点
video that regular expressions can describe many useful languages. We've seen
视频显示正则表达式可以描述许多有用的语言。我们已经看到
some fragments from programming languages but also we saw that e-mail addresses
一些来自编程语言的片段，但我们也看到了电子邮件地址
could be specified this way. Other things that are regular languages are things like
可以这样指定。其他属于常规语言的东西是类似于
phone numbers and file names are also regular. And there are many, many examples
电话号码和文件名也是常规的。有很多很多的例子
in everyday life where regular languages are used to describe some simple set of
在日常生活中，常规语言被用来描述一些简单的
strings. And I also want to emphasize that so far, we've used regular languages as a
弦。我还想强调的是，到目前为止，我们使用常规语言作为
language specification. We use it to define the set of strings we're interested
语言规范。我们使用它来定义我们感兴趣的字符串集
in. But, we haven't said anything about how to actually implement lexical
在……里面。但是，我们还没有谈到如何实际实现词法
analysis. We still need an implementation. And that's what we'll talk about in future
分析。我们仍然需要一个实现。这就是我们将来要讨论的问题
videos. In particular, in particular, we're going to look at the problem of
视频。特别是，我们要特别关注的问题是
given a string as an irregular expression. Or, how do we know whether that string is
给定一个字符串作为不规则表达式。或者，我们如何知道该字符串是否
in the language of the regular expression are.
正则表达式的语言是。